http://www.nait.ca/privacy

Popular Pages:
Parking
Locations & Maps
How to Apply
Library
What can we help you find?:
Staff Email
Forgot Password?
Education Abroad
Contact the International Centre Phone: 780.378.6130 Email: internationalcentre@nait.ca Hours: 8 a.m. - 4 p.m.
Current Students
Information for:
Home
»About NAIT » Corporate Structure » Legal, Policies & Reporting » Disclaimers » Privacy Policy
Freedom of Information
What is a Record?
What does Custody and Control mean?
We value your privacy
The Northern Alberta Institute of Technology ("NAIT") is committed to ensuring the personal privacy of faculty, staff, students, and customers visiting our website. The following information discloses our practices regarding:
Collecting data, including what type of information is gathered and tracked
Why this information is being collected, and how this information is used
The following guidelines were developed with a fundamental respect for our users' right to privacy. NAIT reserves the right to modify our privacy policy at any time. Any such modification will be effective immediately upon posting to the NAIT website.
Providing consent
By using this website, you agree to our use of cookies during your browsing experience. Your session and the pages you visit on www.NAIT.ca will be tracked, but you will remain anonymous.
Information collected by NAIT
A web traffic analysis tool is used by NAIT in order to collect information from visits to our website. The data we attain by using this software helps us understand the traffic patterns and types of technology our visitors use. Statistics are generated from this content so that we can personalize and continually improve your online experience.
The information we collect helps us identify the following:
The Internet domain and IP address from which you access the NAIT website
The type of browser and operating system used to access the site
The pages that were visited
The date and time the site was accessed
Average time spent on the site
Popular search phrases
Use of information
All personal information that is collected is managed in accordance with the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act. This means that, at the point of collection, you will be informed that your personal information is being collected; the purpose for which it is being collected, and that you have a right to access the collected information.
NAIT will not reveal any personal information that users provide to any third party without the users' permission. Access to personal information is restricted to those NAIT employees who require this information in order to provide requested products or services. Upon request, NAIT will remove users (and their information) from our database or permit them to "opt-out" of any further email newsletters or contact.
Understanding cookies
Some of NAIT’s web pages and applications use cookies. Cookies are short and simple text files that are sent through a web browser and stored on your system. If you are concerned about cookies, refer to the help menu in your browser for information on how to disable cookies. Browsers may also be enabled to notify you when a website is attempting to send a cookie to your machine.
NAIT may use cookies for the following reasons:
To monitor usage and improve the performance of the website
To help websites remember who you are, and what other websites you have visited recently to offer personalized content
To enable browsers to save authentication details and/or preferences for you so that you will not have to re-enter them the next time you visit the website
Analytics Services
NAIT uses various analytics services, such as Google Analytics, to measure traffic patterns to, from, and within the website. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the website is transmitted to various analytics service providers’ servers both inside and outside Canada. NAIT uses the statistical reports generated by analytics services to continually improve our web presence and help make our website more useful for visitors.
Content Personalization and Remarketing
As part of NAIT’s marketing initiatives, we use an advertising practice called remarketing, which allows us to track the activity of users who have visited the website as they continue to other areas of the internet. This may involve the use of cookies. Because of remarketing campaigns, third-party entities (such as Google or Facebook, for example) may display advertising or messaging from NAIT when you visit other sites on the internet.
NAIT’s data protection and retention policy
NAIT keeps your Personal Information for as long as needed to fulfill the particular purpose for which it was collected. We may also retain your records if legally required or to fulfill a legitimate interest.
Transactions where information enters a system of records
Where personal information is provided that enters a system of records, it is collected in compliance with section 33 (c) of the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act. NAIT collects, creates and maintains information for the purposes of admission, registration and other activities directly related to its educational programming. Information collected is only kept for the length of time necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected.
Legal, Policies & Reporting
NAIT Policies & Procedures
Institutional Reports
Salary Disclosures
Frequently Asked Questions
Public Disclosure of Expenses
Disclaimers
NAIT Website Terms of Use
What is a Record?
What does Custody and Control mean?
CareersEmergencyLibrary ServicesParkingProtective ServicesTechnical SupportSupport NAIT
Northern Alberta Institute of Technology
Contact Us
The Student Service Centre is here to help you on your path to academic success.
Phone: 780.471.6248
Toll Free: 1.877.333.6248
Fax: 780.471.8490
Email NAIT
Not a current or prospective student? Visit the Contact page for more information.
Website Feedback
Privacy PolicyTerms of UseFOIPCredit Card PaymentsStaff Portal
